technocash.com 2010-11-20

# Technocash for Moving Money

Technocash is committed to protecting your privacy. We want to provide you with a service that enhances your life, your personal or business financial transactions, and your Internet shopping experiences, while making sure that your personal privacy is secure. This privacy policy explains more about what personal information we obtain from you, how we obtain it and why, what we do with your personal information, how you can access it, and more. We collect, store and use your personal information in accordance with the National Privacy Principles contained in the _Privacy Act 1988_. Privacy is the core of our philosophy, and we welcome your input and responses to this commitment of ours. Let us know what you think any time by emailing info@technocash.com, or giving us a call.

### Collecting your personal information

#### What information do we ask for?

We will only ever ask you for information that is relevant to the business relationship we have with you, or that we may be required by law to know about you in order for us to provide you with a product or service. For example, when you apply for one of our products or services, we may ask for details such as your name, address, date of birth, and contact details.

We will generally not collect other information that may be more sensitive (such as ethnicity, personal health information, sexual preferences, religious or political views and opinions, or criminal records) unless it is required by law or in relation to a legal or equitable claim, or where we specifically require it to provide your requested product or service and you have provided us with express or implied consent.

#### How do we collect your personal information?

We collect most personal information directly from you. For example, your personal information will be collected when you open a Technocash account, fill in any of our approved application forms for products or services, visit our websites or us in person, or when you deal with us over the telephone or by email. Occasionally we may also be required to gather information about you from a third party, such as a credit reporting agency or government agencies.

#### Why do we collect your personal information?

We will let you know the main reason we collect your personal information when it is requested from you. There are a number of reasons why we collect personal information, however the usual reason is that it is necessary for us to provide you with a product or service, or to perform our functions and activities. For example, we may require information to: evaluate your suitability or eligibility for certain products or services or to recommend other products or services; help you manage or use a product or service; assist in us performing administrative or operational tasks; or investigate a complaint on your behalf. Additionally, collection may sometimes be required for legal reasons, such as to verify your identity. We are sometimes required by law to maintain certain minimum personal details, contact information and transaction-based data for some account types, to satisfy obligations under industry Codes of Conduct and certain legislation. Full details and terms and conditions can be found in the legal section of our website.

### Using your personal information

#### Within Technocash

We may use your personal information within our Company to assist in providing you with a product or service, for general customer service reasons, or to assist us in performing administrative or operational tasks.

#### Disclosure to third parties

Sometimes we provide personal information about customers to organisations outside of Technocash. Generally this will only occur when the organisation or other entity helps us with our business. For example: outsourced service providers including mailing houses or telemarketing agencies; authorised representatives of Technocash; other financial institutions; credit reporting agencies; and our accountants, auditors or lawyers. We limit the information we provide others. We provide no more than what they require to assist us with the relevant aspect of our business. Where we do provide personal information to others, we ensure that it is only used for legitimate and required purposes. We also enter into contractual arrangements with third parties which generally spell out strict personal information and privacy standards.

#### Marketing

We may use your personal information to offer you products and services we believe may interest you, or to update you in relation to relevant new product features, services, or Company developments. We will not contact you for such purposes if you request us not to. If you do not wish to receive such marketing offers or other information please let us know at any time and we will act promptly on your request.

#### Required disclosure of information

As you would expect, certain organizations, government agencies and regulatory authorities have legal access to our data and we fully co-operate with bona fide entities requesting information. These may include, for example, Central Banks, State or Federal police, and other appropriate Australian and international Government and non-Government authorities, agencies and organisations.

### Security of your personal information

Personal information that we hold about you is protected against misuse, loss, and unauthorised access, modification or disclosure. We have strict operating procedures and protocols ensuring this protection.

We use our best endeavours to ensure that your personal information is only accessible by vetted and duly authorised people. It may be stored in hardcopy or electronically, and is protected by physical security measures (such as locks and security systems) as well as computer and network security measures (such as firewalls, encryption, identification codes and passwords).

Additionally, we destroy personal information that is no longer needed, either by properly disposing of paper files, letters, correspondence and hardcopy documents, or by deleting electronic documents from our systems.

### Keeping your personal information up-to-date

We take reasonable steps to ensure your personal information that is collected by us is accurate, complete and up-to-date. We encourage you to help us by telling us immediately if you change any of your contact details. BillFold account holders can even log in to their account and update their contact details where these have changed, and variations will automatically be recorded in our systems.

#### Accessing your personal information

You are able to access the personal information that we have about you. You can also ask for any corrections to be made. All you need to do is contact us at any time, using our contact details per the "Contact Us" section of our website. You will not be charged for any request in relation to accessing or updating your personal information.

There are limited circumstances in which we will not be able to provide you with details, such as where doing so would reveal personal information about another person or reveal a commercially sensitive decision-making process, where we are restricted by law from doing so, or where the information relates to existing or anticipated legal proceedings.

### Your personal information and certain Technocash products

**(i) TECHNOCASH "digital-cash"**

TECHNOCASH "digital-cash" was designed to be intrinsically anonymous and private. We transact using SSL to ensure that your transactions with your TECHNOCASH "digital cash" are encrypted. We are capable of 128bit encryption.

An important thing to remember is that we protect your personal information: we do not "mine" any of our data records that contain your personal information for on-sale or use by third parties except as agreed to by you. If you choose to participate in any of our specials or promotions, we may have your contact details for internal use or the use stated at the time of the special or promotion to which you will have agreed. We reserve the right to from time to time inform you of promotional and other offers, whether or not in conjunction with our merchants, based on individual TECHNOCASH details such as "remaining value", and to place these offers where appropriate. Usually all we will need is an email address to contact you on. In any case, it is our policy to honour the "unsubscribe" option to any mailing lists we may have.

**(ii) BillFold Accounts**

BillFold products are account-based systems for loading and dispersing TECHNOCASH "digital-cash."

A BillFold allows you to enter and store personal and business information. Indeed, some BillFolds are fully identified: for example, Retail BillFolds disclose merchant details so that shoppers can have the peace of mind that they are interacting with a known merchant.

The BillFold system also serves to connect Organizations to their members' BillFolds, via messaging systems, payment dispersal systems, and payment collections. If your BillFold account is set up as a member of an Organization BillFold, it is possible for the Organization to store membership data about you including your name, phone and other contact details, bank account details, and BillFold account number. Certain Organization membership benefits may require further data to operate effectively.

### Resolving your concerns

If you believe that your privacy has been compromised, you are entitled to complain. If you have a complaint, it is important to let us know. We want to hear from you. Your feedback could alert us to problems that we are unaware of, and provides us with an opportunity to fix those problems.

We can process any complaint confidentially at your request, and our complaints handling procedures come at no expense to you. Throughout the process we will keep you informed as to:

  * Your contact person.
  * The progress of your complaint.
  * Information as to our decisions and the reasons for them.

Our aim is to resolve complaints quickly, and we are confident that most problems should be easily resolved within a short period of time. A simple complaint should be resolved with 2 working days and more complex matters within 5 working days. If more time is required to resolve or investigate your complaint you will be advised by your nominated preferred contact method.

If you feel your complaint has not been satisfactorily handled or resolved following this process, you can contact us for more details about our independent External Dispute Resolution scheme. Technocash is a member of the Financial Ombudsman Service.

To submit a complaint, please fill in the [feedback form at www.technocash.com](http://www.technocash.com/pages/feedback.cfm). Alternatively, you can contact us by phoning 1300 137 494 or +612 96871900, or sending us a fax to +612 96871911. You can also address your complaint in writing to "Feedback" at: PO BOX 618 Parramatta NSW 2124 Australia.
